<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://fahrenheitrobotics.org/site/blog</id>
    <title>Fahrenheit Robotics Blog</title>
    <updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://fahrenheitrobotics.org/site/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Fahrenheit Robotics Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://fahrenheitrobotics.org/site/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Newsletter - First Issue]]></title>
        <id>https://fahrenheitrobotics.org/site/blog/newsletter-issue-1</id>
        <link href="https://fahrenheitrobotics.org/site/blog/newsletter-issue-1"/>
        <updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[🔥 Fahrenheit Robotics Team Newsletter - Premier Issue 🔥]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>🔥 Fahrenheit Robotics Team Newsletter - Premier Issue 🔥</p>
<p>Welcome Students, Mentors, Family, and Friends to the very first edition of our team’s newsletter!</p>
<p>In this issue, you’ll find:
🔥 A survey asking for your help to decide what we call the Survey
🔥 Build Season Highlights
🔥 Calls to Action and how to stay in touch</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="vote-for-newsletter-name">Vote for Newsletter Name<a href="https://fahrenheitrobotics.org/site/blog/newsletter-issue-1#vote-for-newsletter-name" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Vote for Newsletter Name" title="Direct link to Vote for Newsletter Name">​</a></h2>
<p>We plan to send out a newsletter like this periodically to keep everyone aware of what the team is up to and spread awareness about FIRST Robotics. We need your help to know what to call our Newsletter? Please submit your vote below!</p>
<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeegt_XlNxynxHsU6L0fLS5Tv6FAAqplAI5JfsdU5CO0gfnlA/viewform" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Vote for our Team Newsletter name here!</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="build-season">Build Season<a href="https://fahrenheitrobotics.org/site/blog/newsletter-issue-1#build-season" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Build Season" title="Direct link to Build Season">​</a></h2>
<p>Each year, on the first Saturday of the year, <a href="https://www.firstinspires.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">FIRST</a> has the season kickoff.</p>
<p>This year's theme was an Ocean theme called <a href="https://www.firstinspires.org/robotics/frc/game-and-season" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reefscape</a>. This year, robots needed to manipulate "coral" (pvc pipe segments) onto a "reef" (a large metal bar structure). Robots can also score by grabbing "algae" (large rubber balls) and depositing them into a "processor" or into a net. In case you aren't familar with the competition rules for this year, check out <a href="https://youtu.be/YWbxcjlY9JY?si=EYqdJJVxP4pZ3Xwv" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this introductory video</a> to understand the game.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-plan">The Plan<a href="https://fahrenheitrobotics.org/site/blog/newsletter-issue-1#the-plan" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Plan" title="Direct link to The Plan">​</a></h3>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="swerve-drive">Swerve Drive!<a href="https://fahrenheitrobotics.org/site/blog/newsletter-issue-1#swerve-drive" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Swerve Drive!" title="Direct link to Swerve Drive!">​</a></h4>
<p>In previous years, the team has used a tank drive similar to <a href="https://www.andymark.com/products/am14u6-with-no-gearboxes?via=Z2lkOi8vYW5keW1hcmsvV29ya2FyZWE6OkNhdGFsb2c6OkNhdGVnb3J5LzVhZjhkN2Y1YmM2ZjZkNWUzNmYyMzRkOA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this one here</a>. Tank drives are great at going forward and back ward and pusing other robots around. But it takes time to turn and maneuver. We had been discussion alternative drives since the offseason last year. In fact we experimented with a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mecanum_wheel" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">mechanum drive</a> during our practice competition in the Fall. But what we really wanted was swerve drive! So, we researched and decided this season was the year to take the plunge. We bought our Swerve Drive from Rev Robotics. Thanks to some of our previous mentors, we were put in contact with another FIRST team in Florida who had just started using swerve drive last season. The students organized a Zoom meeting and the Florida team shared a wealth of experience about how to build, code, and maintain swerve. So, we bought a <a href="https://www.revrobotics.com/rev-25-3270/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rev Robotics Swerve Drive</a> and got anxiously waited for the package to arrive.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="elevator">Elevator<a href="https://fahrenheitrobotics.org/site/blog/newsletter-issue-1#elevator" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Elevator" title="Direct link to Elevator">​</a></h4>
<p>Building an elevator was another new experience for the team this year. The team's plan was to mount the elevator onto the swerve drive train and then eventually also add a mechanism to the elevator that could catch Coral from the Human Player and then score the coral on level 1, 2, and 3. We researched options and decided to purchace <a href="https://www.thethriftybot.com/products/thrifty-elevator-stage-kit" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this elevator kit from Thriftybot</a>.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="reversible-bumpers">Reversible Bumpers<a href="https://fahrenheitrobotics.org/site/blog/newsletter-issue-1#reversible-bumpers" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Reversible Bumpers" title="Direct link to Reversible Bumpers">​</a></h4>
<p>First competitions are made up of matches. Each match includes 3 robots on the blue alliance playing against 3 robots on the red alliance. During competitions teams are randomly placed on either the red or blue alliance for each match. Teams must change the color of bumpers on their robot to match the color of the alliance for each match.</p>
<p>Normally, our team builds 2 sets of bumpers: 1 blue set and 1 red set. We can then detach and re-attach the correct color bumper to match our alliance color for each match during competitions. We notice a few teams last season who, what we thought, was a very cool idea to build a single bumper and used their sewing skills and a little velcro to put both blue and red fabric on the bumpers. This way, they could leave the bumpers attached and easily reverse the fabric by unvelcroing and re-velcroing the correct color fabric. We thought this was pretty cool idea and were excited that it might save us some hassel. That was the idea at least!</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-build">The Build<a href="https://fahrenheitrobotics.org/site/blog/newsletter-issue-1#the-build" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Build" title="Direct link to The Build">​</a></h3>
<p>The team met consistently 2-3 times a week for the 2 months leading up to our first competition. One group of students worked steadily to build both the Rev Swerve drive and a Thrifty Bot Elevator. Another group worked on building the reversible fabric bumpers.</p>
<p>Another great aspect of FIRST competitions is meeting and getting to know other teams. During competitions, each teams sets up a "pit" where they can work on the robot. As long as safety goggles are warn, students, mentors, judges, family and friends are welcome to walk around the pits during competitions to see the different robots and collect swag such as buttons and flyers. So, another group of our students worked on designing artwork and producing buttons to hand out.</p>
<p>This is the first season the team has started to use Computer Aided Design. During the offseason we had several sessions where we learned how to use an online CAD program called <a href="https://www.onshape.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Onshape</a>. Here's the design we had for the Robot after the first few weeks of build season.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="robot in onshape" src="https://fahrenheitrobotics.org/site/assets/images/cad-3cc50ece076690e396e4fb0737668bdd.png" width="1478" height="1306" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>If you're intereated you can view the actual CAD in your browser <a href="https://cad.onshape.com/documents/a22a39e157b5af2a791cb649/w/45a0f9ccefe88d22eea74af4/e/66bd5f9525a5a97b00942456?renderMode=0&amp;uiState=67e7eba70da54a7efcd25f7b" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">by clicking here</a>. We hope to continue learning and improving our CAD skills. It's a very powerful design tool.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-result">The Result<a href="https://fahrenheitrobotics.org/site/blog/newsletter-issue-1#the-result" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Result" title="Direct link to The Result">​</a></h3>
<p>With about 2 weeks before our first competition, we had our swerve drive and elevator built. Bumpers were half way complete.</p>
<p>We had yet to complete the electrical wiring and coding in order to really have the robot working nicely. We had a prototype but still hadn't started building a scoring mechanism to intake the coral.</p>
<p>So, during the last few weeks of build season, the students decided to meet Mon-Friday and also extend meetings by an extra hour to try to complete all the tasks before our first competition!</p>
<p>They worked hard to finish putting fabric on the bumpers, finish the wiring, and we were even able to do a first encouraging test of the code for our swerve drive.</p>
<p>We also cobbled together a very crude scoring mechanism.</p>
<p>Here's a picture of what the robot looked like right before our first Competition in Portsmouth:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="robot at end of build season" src="https://fahrenheitrobotics.org/site/assets/images/IMG_0197-ec4bf4b9efb26340dbc0a918a2a14e53.jpg" width="1084" height="1444" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>And here was the attempt at a scoring mechanism that we could attach to the elevator:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="coral scoring mechanism" src="https://fahrenheitrobotics.org/site/assets/images/IMG_0198-02e2e7efb4b66df92d2f72441c07f88d.jpg" width="1084" height="1444" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>As you can see, we took on quite a lot of new challenges this year: using CAD for the first time, a new swerve drive, building an elevator for the first time, and reversable bumpers.</p>
<p>Given the small size of the team, and our ambitious plans, I'm very impressed and proud of what the team was able to accomplish this build season! The students not only worked hard, but we also had a lot fun and learned a ton, in a relaxed, enjoyable atmosphere.</p>
<p>... stay tuned for next issue to find out what happened during our first competition!</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="call-to-action">Call to Action<a href="https://fahrenheitrobotics.org/site/blog/newsletter-issue-1#call-to-action" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Call to Action" title="Direct link to Call to Action">​</a></h2>
<p>We'd like to spread more awareness of our team throughout the Fredericksburg Community and could use your help.</p>
<p>We would love to attract more members and sponsors to build our team towards a more competitive level. If you know of any community events where we could attend and advertise our team, send us an email at <code>fahrenheitrobotics@gmail.com</code>.</p>
<p>You can also always visit our Website for links to our Discord and Facebook pages to stay in touch!</p>
<p><a href="https://fahrenheitrobotics.org/#contact" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://fahrenheitrobotics.org/#contact</a></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Dave Paroulek</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/upgradingdave</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="newsletter" term="newsletter"/>
    </entry>
</feed>